- 0812-6329-9950
- ★ fahmi.intelligo.id
- Bandung, Indonesia

Muhammad Fahmi

Freelance and Instructor Data Science | Data Scientist



SUMMARY

Hello, I'm Fahmi. Have an interest in working in an adaptable environment. Skilled in Analytical Thinking, Data Scientist and Python. Has experience focusing on Natural Language Processing and Data Mining. And I work as a Freelance and Instructor.

SKILLS

Python

Machine Learning

Data Mining

Natural Language Processing

Deep Learning

OpenCV

Tableau

Google Data Studio

Scraping - Selenium

Github

Figma

Leadership

Team Work

Problem Solving

Creativity

Critical

Public Speaking

LANGUAGES

Indonesia Native
English Basic

CERTIFICATES

Microsoft Certified Azure Al Fundamentals

09/2021 - Present

Junior Web Programming - Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi

09/2019 - 09/2022

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

NoLimit Indonesia

04/2022 - Present

Instructor - Data, Business Analytics and Operations

Ruangguru.com · Part-time

02/2022 - Present

Become an instructor at the Studi Independen Ruangguru x Kampus Mederka, Ruangguru CAMP (Career Acceleration Bootcamp)

Instructor - Python Data Science - Part time

Kodehive (PT Kode Gama Teknologi)

12/2021 - Present

Create a Short Learning Video About Data Science, become a mentor at the Data Science Bootcamp

Data Science Tutor

Superprof

02/2021 - Present

Tutoring about: Data Science, Data Analyst, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Python, Web Basic etc.

Super teacher predicate, top 5 for search for data science and python.

Freelance Data Scientist

Freelance

07/2020 - Present

Freelance about: Data Science, Data Analyst, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Python, Web Basic etc

Managed to get approximately 50 clients in teaching courses online.

Lead Data Scientist - Intern

Kebun Pintar

07/2021 - 03/2022

Data Scientist

PT Bank Mandiri (Persero) Tbk. · Freelance

11/2021 - 12/2021

I am a data scientist working on the Talent Score Card project at Setneg in collaboration with myself. Create a recommendation system using the similarities between data and natural language processing.

EDUCATION

Informatics Engineering

Politeknik Pos Indonesia 2021

Applied Bachelor Degree

GPA: 3,54/4

Project:

- Project I Implementation of Smart Box Logistics
- Project II Human Brain Wave Detection
- Project III Automatic Door Face Recognition using Arduino and Python

Organizational Experience:

- Head of the Syi'ar Department of Muslim Organizations (Lembaga Dakwah Kampus) | 2018 - 2019
- Minister of Communications and Informatics of Student Executive Board (Badan Eksekutif Mahasiswa) | 2018-2019

Volunteers & Training:

- Design and Media Class Speaker held by Muslim Organizations | 2020
- Python Training Speaker, Become a teacher in Python language training activities for beginners | 2019
- Became the Head of the division in the lyale West Java community service activity | 2018

Achievements and Awards:

- PT Pos Indonesia Scholarship | 2018 and 2019
- Become a Participant in the Higher Education LLDIKTI Innovation Exhibition | 2019
- Become a winner in the videography competition at the BYMC LDK Baraya activity | 2018

Data Science

DQLab.id

Non Formal

Natural Sciences Major

SMA Negeri 2 Kisaran

2017

Senior Highschool

Head Of Academy Division - Student Ambassador

BISA AI Academy (PT BISA ARTIFISIAL INDONESIA)

04/2021 - 07/2021

Became Head of the Academy Division for Student Ambassador

- · Manage Team
- · Data Science Speakers of Webinar
- Promotion

Academy Divison - Student Ambassador

BISA AI Academy (PT BISA ARTIFISIAL INDONESIA)

04/2021 - 04/2021

Data Analyst

Kebun Pintar

03/2021 - 07/2021

Student Ambassador

BISA AI Academy (PT BISA ARTIFISIAL INDONESIA)

02/2021 - 03/2021

Data Scientist - Internship

PT. Telekomunikasi Indonesia Tbk Direktorat Digital Business (TELKOM DDB)

08/2020 - 01/2021

· Business Understanding

Conduct business understanding to work on recommendation system projects related to what training is suitable for employees.

· Data Understanding

Understand what data is needed to obtain a recommendation system built solutions.

· Web Scraping

Data collection using selenium python from online course websites.

· Data Preprocessing/Cleaning.

Cleaning data from data that has been collected.

• Recommendation System

Make a recommendation system regarding what training is suitable for holding.

• Emerging Topic Recommendation

Make recommendations on what topics are trending in 2021.

Web Developer

Visualization to website.

Website Administrator And Marketing

Pisang Mesir Indonesia (Retail)

08/2018 - 08/2019

- · Website Administrator
- Digital Marketing Instagram
- Sales